# Hanju Yoo

School of Integrated Technology, Yonsei University hanju.yoo@yonsei.ac.kr

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Ph.D. student researching for deep learning for communications and information theory for deep learning at the Intelligence Networking Lab., Yonsei University, Korea. Before joining the lab, I earned a B.E. from the School of Integrated Technology at Yonsei University, graduating with the highest honors. My research interest includes semantic communications, learned image compression, and computer vision. I was an exhibitor at CES 2023 on behalf of Yonsei University, and am a recipient of the 2022 Qualcomm IT Tour Program. Committed to community engagement, I have served as a teaching assistant for three years and have two years of student council experience. I also love to solve real-world problems by creating automated, sustainable, and systematic solutions.

#### **EDUCATION**

2021 — Present	Yonsei University	Seoul, Korea
	Ph.D. Student (Advisor: Prof. Chan-Byoung Chae)	
2018 - 2021	Yonsei University	Seoul, Korea
	B.E. Integrated Technology (GPA: 4.15/4.3, Graduated with Highest Honors)	

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Y. Kim, H.-J. Moon, **H. Yoo**, B.-N. Kim, K.-K. Wong, and C.-B. Chae, "A State-of-the Art Survey on Full Duplex Network Design," under revision for *Proc. IEEE*
- 2. **H. Yoo**, L. Dai, S. Kim, and C.-B. Chae, "On the Role of CNN and ViT on Semantic Communications: Analysis and Prototype Validation," *IEEE Access*, vol. 11, pp. 71528-71541, July 2023
- 3. **H. Yoo**, L. Dai, S. Kim, and C.-B. Chae, "Real-Time Semantic Communications With a Vision Transformer," *IEEE Int. Conf. Commun. Workshops (ICC WKSHPS)*, May 2022

### AWARDS AND HONORS

Feb. 2023	Exhibitor, CES 2023
	Demonstrated real-time wireless semantic communications testbed in behalf of Yonsei college of engineering.
Aug. 2022	Recipient, Qualcomm IT Tour Program
	Participated in the Qualcomm IT Tour, a fully-funded program providing a visit tof Qualcomm's San Diego
	headquarters with executive presentations and networking opportunities.
Feb. 2021	Graduated with Highest Honors
	<1% in college of engineering, ranked 1st
Mar. 2018	Full Scholarship for Undergraduate
	Issued by Ministry of Science and ICT of Korea (MSIP) and National IT Industry Promotion Agency (NIPA)

### **EXPERIENCES**

Mar. 2021 — Dec. 2023	Teaching Assitant, Computationtal Thinking and SW Programming, Yonsei University
	Led weekly 4-hour Python lectures and prepared course materials and exams.
Mar. 2019 — Oct. 2020	Head Developer, Yonsei University Student Council
	Designed and built the website using React and Ruby on Rails, deployed on AWS EC2.

## **PROJECTS**

2011 - 2018	KBoost
	A Windows process cleaner with $50k+$ downloads, featured in IT Donga software reviews <sup>1</sup> .
2020	Python Assignment Evaluator
	https://github.com/kmsiapps/python-assignments-evaluator
	An automated evaluator for Python assignments, featuring score assessment and diff visualization.
2021	PMSim
	https://github.com/kmsiapps/pmsim
	A VM migration simulator for online IDE service, incorporating a novel load-prediction algorithm designed to optimize VM migrations and fully utilize the capacity of physical machines.
	J

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>https://it.donga.com/23713/

# **SKILLS**

- $\bullet$  Languages: Korean (Native), English (Fluent, TEPS 521)
- Foundational Expertise in EECS: Communications Theory, Computer Networks, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Parallel/GPU Computing, Compiler Design, and Computational Theory
- Programming: Python, Matlab, Tensorflow, C/C++ (Fluent), Javascript, Ruby, CUDA, LabVIEW (Intermediate)